Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/ beatricegraupner (LinkedIn)

Top-Kenntnisse

Teamwork
Political Science
Policy Analysis

Languages

Portuguese (Limited Working)
Korean (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Professional Working)
French (Limited Working)
German (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Female Empowerment Program German Academic Exchange

Service (DAAD) English Certificate
Guest Lecturer at the SNSPA Online
International Week 2020

Professional Skills Curriculum Award

Beatrice Graupner

Public Affairs Advisor | #30u30 | MBA Candidate | Ex-Tesla Berlin

Zusammenfassung

Public affairs enthusiast located in Berlin.

In 2018 I finished my postgraduate degree at the University of St Andrews. My university studies in three different countries have shaped me to be ambitious and enthusiastic. I am passionate about global policy and politics. My intellectual curiosity in security and strategy drives me to travel and learn about institutional and legal frameworks. My work ethic has helped me gain insights into lobbyism, defence, and governmental processes.

I love meeting new people, gaining more experience, and learning new languages.

Please feel free to get in touch.

Berufserfahrung

Deutsche Bahn
Official Advisor Public Affairs - Environment and Sustainability
März 2021 - Present (1 Jahr 1 Monat)
Berlin, Germany

Intuitive

Public Affairs Specialist for Middle and Eastern Europe Juli 2020 - Februar 2021 (8 Monate)

Berlin, Germany

Evaluated and monitored political developments relevant for the company.

- Developed messaging and materials for a variety of internal and external audiences, particularly policymakers and influencers.
- Executed campaigns, identified, engaged, and managed stakeholders.
- Conceptualised, developed, prepared, and executed stakeholder audience and policy focused meetings, events and activities in the company's Berlin office.

- Coordinated with public affairs agencies and project partners from across the healthcare and health policy community.

Tesla

1 Jahr 8 Monate

Business Resolutions Partner Oktober 2019 - Juli 2020 (10 Monate)

Berlin, Deutschland

Developed expertise on, and determined viable solutions, for assets subject to contract obligation disputes with consideration for the customer experience, as well as financial and operational implications.

- Recommended, developed, implemented and managed appropriate courses of action taking into account the best interests of the company, the investor, and the customer.
- Managed key internal and external stakeholders to resolve projects effectively and promptly, ensuring multiple departments adhere to deadlines.
- Drove other projects as required or as business needs changed.

Government Relations Coordinator for Germany, Austria and Switzerland (DACH)

Dezember 2018 - Oktober 2019 (11 Monate)

Berlin Area, Germany

Monitored all local government affairs activities, advocated for Tesla's position in relevant policy and lawmaking processes, monitored and researched current and emerging government affairs issues.

- Established and built relationships with members of the EV community.
- Collaborated cross-functionally with other Tesla teams both locally and globally (commercial, legal, communications, charging, energy, etc.) to quickly identify risks and opportunities.
- Communicated and worked effectively with internal and external stakeholders, including Tesla senior management and high-level government officials, to achieve optimal policy outcomes.
- Facilitated to accelerate governments' adoption for EV market options.

FDP Freie Demokraten

Research Assistant and Political Monitoring Specialist at the National Party Office

Februar 2017 - April 2017 (3 Monate)

Berlin, Germany

Appointment preparation for the federal executive director, secretary-general, and the federal chairman.

- Researched data of public policy topics and curated systematic overviews for various teams.
- Assisted the electoral campaign and program development teams.
- Analysed social media data.
- Answered citizen and enterprise requests.

BVMed - Bundesverband Medizintechnologie Political-Lobbyism and Public Affairs Analyst Februar 2016 - April 2016 (3 Monate) Berlin, Germany

German Medical Technology Association

- Composed a thesis about digitalisation possibilities and processes for the German Medical Technology Industry which has 27 billion Euros in production.
- Presentations with political institutions and associations
- Participation at information events about medical devices, e-Commerce rulings, and legal bases relating to medical engineering products

Katholische Universität Eichstätt-Ingolstadt Student Assistant at Institute for General Sociology and Sociological Theory

April 2015 - Juli 2015 (4 Monate)

Eichstätt, Germany

Supportive organisation and participation in public events. Management of diverse tasks assigned from the academic staff.

Auswärtiges Amt (Federal Foreign Office) Germany Portuguese-German Relationship Monitoring at the Honorary Consulate of the Republic of Germany

Februar 2012 - Februar 2012 (1 Monat)

Funchal / Madeira, Portugal

Cônsul Honorário da República Federal da Alemanha no Funchal (Madeira)

Ausbildung

Quadriga University of Applied Sciences

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Public Affairs and Leadership · (2020 - 2022)

University of St Andrews

Master of Letters - MLitt. (Magister Litterarum), Strategic Studies · (2017 - 2018)

서강대학교

Semester Abroad, Seoul / South Korea, Political Science - International Relations · (2016 - 2016)

Catholic University of Eichstätt-Ingolstadt

Bachelor of Arts - B.A., Political Science and Sociology · (2014 - 2017)